printf is a predefined function.
It comes from the header file stdio.h 
It takes data from the program and
transfers the same into stdout.

stdout is the stream (channel) of 
data transfer between the application
and the monitor.

printf can output 3 types of data.
1) Data enclosed in double quotes.
2) Special signs, symbols and cursor movement characters.
3) Data stored in variables.


Using printf to output special signs, symbols and for cursor movement
------------------------------------------------------------
\n : Line feed and carriage return. Moves the cursor to the next line
\t : Moves the cursor one tab position rightwards
\r : Carriage return. Moves the cursor to beginning of current line
\b : Backspace. Moves the cursor one position leftwards.
\a : Alert. Plays a beep sound using the CPU speaker.
\\ : To print \
\" : To print "
\' : To print '
%% : To print %
\1 : To print ☺
\2 : To print ☻
\3 : To print ♥
\4 : To print ♦
\5 : To print ♣
\6 : To print ♠


Using printf to output data stored in variables
-------------------------------------------
printf can be used to output data stored
in variables.

Syntax :
 printf("formatCharacter", variable);

Format characters are indicators 
for the output form of variable data.

%d, %x, %X, %o, %i, %u are used to 
output data of a whole number in 
decimal, hexadecimal, HEXADECIMAL,
octal integer and unsigned decimal form 
respectively.

Similarly printf supports use of
%c for outputting char variables.
%f for outputting float and double variables.
%s for outputting Strings.

FYI :   
In the term printf, "f" stands for use 
of "format characters" for dealing with 
variables of multiple different types. 
